=The Origin of Eternity=
= أصل الخلود =
=Episode 14=
= الحلقة 14 =
My Lord.
ربي.
Her Majesty placed me in a period of solitude.
وضعتني جلالة الملكة في فترة من العزلة.
Why do you come here?
لماذا أتيت إلى هنا؟
My Lord, you failed to notice that someone is making fool of you.
ربي ، لقد فشلت في ملاحظة أن أحدًا ما يخدعك.
If I don't come to remind you,
إذا لم آتي لتذكيرك ،
the Great Sheng
شنغ العظيم
is soon to be overthrown by the Ling Empire.
قريبًا من قبل إمبراطورية لينغ.
We had a strife at the court
كان لدينا فتنة في المحكمة
because of the 100,000 Ling soldiers.
بسبب 100000 جندي لينغ.
Have you ever thought
هل فكرت يوما
that the lives of the Ling soldiers
أن حياة جنود لينغ
were what I asked for?
كان ما طلبت؟
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
If it wasn't your idea,
إذا لم تكن فكرتك ،
was it Her Majesty?
هل كانت صاحبة الجلالة؟
Her Majesty became besotted with the Crown Prince.
أصبحت جلالة الملكة محاصرة مع ولي العهد.
So the said soldiers' lives were saved
لذلك تم إنقاذ حياة الجنود المذكورين
because she was blinded by her obsession.
لأنها أعمت بسبب هوسها.
However,
لكن،
if Her Majesty were to give birth to a son or a daughter
إذا كانت صاحبة الجلالة ستلد ابنا أو ابنة
of that Crown Prince,
من ولي العهد ،
then,
ثم،
he will become the Emperor Emeritus of the Sheng Empire.
سيصبح الإمبراطور الفخري لإمبراطورية شنغ.
Shut it.
أغلقه.
Her Majesty is of noble royal descent
صاحبة الجلالة من أصل ملكي نبيل
and can never be sullied by the Ling people.
ولا يمكن لشعب لينغ أن يلوثه.
True. I always think
حقيقي.  أعتقد دائما
that you're the best candidate for the consort.
أنك أفضل مرشح للقرين.
Yet Bai Ze turns up out of nowhere.
ومع ذلك ، يظهر باي زي من العدم.
Her Majesty likes him.
جلالة الملكة تحبه.
What can I do?
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل؟
True though.
صحيح.
Her Majesty is the monarch
صاحبة الجلالة هي العاهل
and we are her subjects.
ونحن رعاياها.
Only monarch can act as they wish
يمكن للملك فقط التصرف كما يحلو لهم
and love whoever they love.
ويحبون من يحبون.
What are you trying to get at?
ما الذي تحاول الوصول إليه؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
I just feel bad for you.
أنا فقط أشعر بالسوء تجاهك.
Your sincerity has turned in vain.
لقد تحول صدقك عبثا.
Look at what you have done.
انظر إلى ما قمت به.
You left your soldiers out of discipline
لقد تركت جنودك خارج الانضباط
and stay shut in here.
وابقى مغلق هنا.
The soldiers are cheering for Lord Yong in the encampment.
الجنود يهتفون للورد يونغ في المعسكر.
Do you want to rebel?
هل تريد التمرد؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Why do you prefer that useless wimp?
لماذا تفضل ذلك الضعيف عديم الفائدة؟
I'm superior to him all over.
أنا متفوق عليه في كل مكان.
Have many times should I repeat this?
هل يجب علي تكرار هذا مرات عديدة؟
Both of you are different to me.
كلاكما مختلف عني
Deep inside you,
عميقا في داخلك،
I have nothing on him.
ليس لدي أي شيء عليه.
Right?
يمين؟
Fine.
بخير.
I admit this.
أنا أعترف بهذا.
Can I be your secondary husband?
هل يمكنني أن أكون زوجك الثانوي؟
Stop forcing me.
توقف عن إجباري.
Is that really too much to ask?
هل هذا حقا طلب كثير؟
Fine.
بخير.
A paramour or a bedmate?
عشيق أم رفيق الفراش؟
Just give me the position.
فقط أعطني المنصب.
You're only Lord Yong.
أنت فقط اللورد يونغ.
I don't want it.
لا اريدها.
All I ask for is you.
كل ما أطلبه هو أنت.
Are you insane?
هل أنت مجنون؟
As long as you try it,
طالما حاولت ذلك ،
you will know I'm a real man
ستعرف أنني رجل حقيقي
who is way better than that darned Bai Ze.
من هو أفضل بكثير من ذلك المرتب باي زي.
Look at what you have done now.
انظر إلى ما فعلته الآن.
You don't even deserve to compare with him.
أنت لا تستحق حتى المقارنة معه.
Don't force my hand.
لا تجبر يدي.
My Lord, I have passed down your order.
ربي ، لقد مررت أمرك.
All soldiers will not report for duty
لن يقوم جميع الجنود بالخدمة
as long as Her Majesty doesn't resume you back to the court.
طالما أن صاحبة الجلالة لا تستأنف عودتك إلى المحكمة.
Well done.
أحسنت.
Go and get some money
اذهب واحصل على بعض المال
to treat a great feast to the soldiers
لتقديم وليمة عظيمة للجنود
and send my thanks to them.
وأرسل لهم شكري.
Thank you, My Lord.
شكرا لك يا سيدي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I want you to know
أريدك أن تعلم
that who is more important to you,
من هو أكثر أهمية بالنسبة لك ،
that wimp or me.
هذا جبان أو أنا.
My Lord.
ربي.
Why are you still sitting here
لماذا ما زلت جالسا هنا
when trouble is soon befalling you?
متى ستواجهك المتاعب قريبا؟
Hmph, I sit here
همف ، أجلس هنا
because of Her Majesty's order.
بأمر من جلالة الملكة.
The soldiers refuse to report for duty
الجنود يرفضون الحضور للواجب
and appeal for your sake.
والاستئناف من أجلك.
Is that your idea?
هل هذه فكرتك
My Lord, you're sending yourself to your demise.
ربي ، أنت ترسل نفسك إلى زوالك.
No monarch can tolerate
لا يمكن لأي ملك أن يتسامح معه
if the soldiers refuse to listen to them,
إذا رفض الجنود الاستماع إليهم ،
but a general.
لكن جنرال.
(I want her to know)
(أريدها أن تعرف)
(she will only be regarded as the empress)
(ستُعتبر الإمبراطورة فقط)
(if I approve of her.)
(إذا وافقت عليها).
(Her Majesty has already been bewitched by Bai Ze)
(صاحبة الجلالة قد سحرها باي زي بالفعل)
(and neglected the states.)
(وأهمل الدول).
(All the officials have disapproved of her for long.)
(رفضها جميع المسؤولين لفترة طويلة).
(Why don't I take this opportunity)
(لماذا لا أغتنم هذه الفرصة)
(to take over her throne?)
(لتتولى عرشها؟)
(I will kill Bai Ze)
(سأقتل باي زي)
(and confer her as my empress consort.)
(ومنحها قرينة الإمبراطورة.)
(Kill two birds with one stone.)
(ضرب عصفورين بحجر واحد.)
Have you done reviewing the memorandums?
هل انتهيت من مراجعة المذكرات؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
Because
لأن
there is a beauty
هناك جمال
sitting beside me,
جالس بجانبي ،
my mind
عقلي
is distracted.
يصرف.
To not distract you,
حتى لا يشتت انتباهك ،
I shall take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
Don't be shy.
لا تخجل.
Bad news, Your Majesty!
أخبار سيئة يا جلالة الملك!
How bad?
كم سيئ؟
Go on.
تابع.
Lord Yong claimed that he will clean up the evils beside the empress.
ادعى اللورد يونغ أنه سينظف الشرور بجانب الإمبراطورة.
He led the prisoner army and surrounded the palace.
قاد جيش الأسرى وحاصر القصر.
Clean up the evil?
تنظيف الشر؟
Who is the so-called evil?
من هو الشر المزعوم؟
The person I have been tolerant
الشخص الذي كنت متسامحاً
turned out to be the enemy.
تبين أنه العدو.
How could you turn your back on me and rebel
كيف تدير ظهرك لي وتتمرد
just because of Bai Ze?
فقط بسبب باي زي؟
The one who turned her back on me first
الشخص الذي أدار ظهرها لي أولاً
is you.
هل أنت.
I've promoted you as Lord Yong
لقد قمت بترقيتك بصفتك اللورد يونغ
who has the most powerful person below me.
من لديه أقوى شخص تحتي.
Isn't that enough?
أليس هذا كافيا؟
No.
لا.
It's nowhere near enough.
انها ليست قريبة بما فيه الكفاية.
You only peg me as your dog to fight wars
أنت فقط تربطني كلبك لخوض الحروب
if I'm only Lord Yong.
لو كنت أنا فقط اللورد يونغ.
You will never peg me as a man.
لن تربطني أبدًا كرجل.
You're my bosom friend who has gone through hardships with me.
أنت صديقي الذي مررت بمصاعب معي.
I want to be your man.
اريد ان اكون رجلك.
Seeing you stay so close
رؤيتك تبقى قريبا جدا
to Bai Ze,
أن باي زي ،
I wish I could die.
أتمنى أن أموت.
Go on, then.
يذهب في ذلك الحين.
(Unification Hall)
(قاعة التوحيد)
I wonder why you ask for me, Your Majesty.
أتساءل لماذا تسأل عني يا جلالة الملك.
Issue a decree on my behalf.
إصدار مرسوم نيابة عني.
Lord Yong will be stripped of his title
سيتم تجريد اللورد يونغ من لقبه
and exiled to the boundary
ونفي إلى الحدود
and is never allowed to return.
ولا يُسمح له بالعودة أبدًا.
Your Majesty, Lord Yong has committed treason.
جلالة الملك ، اللورد يونغ قد إرتكب الخيانة.
It's better to destroy the evil forever.
من الأفضل تدمير الشر إلى الأبد.
I have made up my mind.
أنت اتخذت قراري.
Say no more.
قل لا زيادة.
Leave now.
ارحل الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
This liquor is from the Fuchun restaurant.
هذا الخمور من مطعم فوشون.
And these are your favourite dishes.
وهذه هي أطباقك المفضلة.
So, this is my last meal.
إذن ، هذه وجبتي الأخيرة.
Her Majesty is determined to kill you before the public
جلالة الملكة مصممة على قتلك أمام الجمهور
as intimidation for others.
ترهيب للآخرين.
We have tried our best to beg for your sake.
لقد بذلنا قصارى جهدنا للتسول من أجلك.
But Her Majesty didn't change her mind.
لكن جلالة الملكة لم تغير رأيها.
I can't believe she wants to humiliate me like this.
لا أصدق أنها تريد إذلالتي بهذه الطريقة.
I finally come to realise
أخيرا أدركت
that I mean nothing to her.
لا أعني لها شيئًا.
My Lord.
ربي.
Bai Ze is an important figure before Her Majesty.
باي زي شخصية مهمة قبل جلالة الملكة.
If you agree,
إذا وافقت،
I will plead with him for you.
سوف أتوسل معه من أجلك.
Maybe you stand a chance to live.
ربما لديك فرصة للعيش.
I'm
أنا
not a coward.
ليس جبان.
Seeking help from that wimp?
طلب المساعدة من هذا الضعيف؟
I would rather kill myself.
أفضل قتل نفسي.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Qinghuan.
تشينغوان.
♪Wandered off from the crowd♪
تجول بعيدًا عن الحشد ♪
♪As more wonderful things await♪
♪ كما تنتظر المزيد من الأشياء الرائعة
♪A sunset from the past resurfaced♪
انعكاس غروب الشمس من الماضي
♪Thousands of sailboats drifted in the sea of clouds♪
جرفت آلاف المراكب الشراعية في بحر السحب
♪And docked at different piers♪
♪ ورست على أرصفة مختلفة ♪
♪Only the catkin willow and my graying hair remained♪
فقط صفصاف القطة وشعري الشيب بقي
♪Let's take on♪
♪ لنأخذ
♪Another year♪
♪ سنة أخرى ♪
♪I traveled alone toward daytime as I waved aside the night♪
سافرت لوحدي في النهار بينما كنت ألوح جانباً في الليل
♪The tapping rain♪
مطر التنصت ♪
♪Awakened the sorrow♪
أيقظ الحزن
♪I'm crying out in loneliness amid pandemonium♪
♪ أنا أبكي في عزلة وسط الهرج والمرج
♪I endured countless ordeals from worldly entanglement♪
لقد تحملت محن لا حصر لها من التشابك الدنيوي ♪
♪Knowing how difficult things are for the first time♪
معرفة مدى صعوبة الأمور لأول مرة ♪
♪After you overcome the vicissitudes of life♪
بعد أن تتغلب على تقلبات الحياة
♪Only then do you understand the fickleness of the world♪
"عندها فقط تفهم تقلب العالم"
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪
♪I wanted to enjoy the years but it turned into a disaster overnight♪
♪ أردت الاستمتاع بالسنوات لكنها تحولت إلى كارثة بين عشية وضحاها
♪Knowing that I can't turn back time♪
♪ مع العلم أنني لا أستطيع العودة بالزمن ♪
♪You would not be intoxicated by sorrow♪
لن تسكر بالحزن
♪Until you were embroiled in love♪
حتى تتورط في الحب ♪